# Mithul Prakash Rao

# Specialist Software Engineer

Energetic, hardworking, honest and good team player with 6.11 years of experience in Software Development Looking for a challenging position in an organization where I can implement my creative skills in attaining personal and professional goals.



raomithul@gmail.com

🔲 +91 9930506961 💡 Thane, Mumbai

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Specialist Software Engineer**

**Larsen & Toubro Infotech** 04/2019 - Present,

## **Senior Software Engineer**

Sparkt Pvt. Ltd. 06/2018 - 04/2019,

## **Software Developer**

**Infinite Computing Systems** 03/2015 - 06/2018

# **PROJECTS**

#### **Phoenix**

ViacomCbs, US

Phoenix is a Windows and web-based application to facilitate Sales Assistants and Traffic teams at CBS to manage "Ad Sales and Traffic Broadcasting system". Phoenix supports ViacomCBS with technologies surrounding its revenue cycle and ad sales management, so they support the more complex distribution, selling, planning, scheduling, and compliance models that the current marketplace demands or is anticipating.

## **Piramal Capital and Housing Finance**

Piramal Finance, India

PCHF provides customized strategies for institutional and retail investors such as Mumbai Redevelopment Fund focused on slum rehabilitation and Apartment Fund focused on bulk buying individual units (Through Piramal Fund Management) and strategic partnerships with leading global pension funds such as CPPIB, APG and Ivanhoe Cambridge.

#### **Chevron MBA**

Chevron, Thailand

Chevron MBA is an application for oil and gas industry to manage the materials to drill the wells for Chevron Thailand client. It is designed to optimize the ordering of drilling material to meet customer needs

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Have been given 100% rating and awarded outstanding performer from past 2 years. Awarded with Highflier award.

# <u>INTERESTS</u>

Sports, Dancing, Singing

# SKILLS

Hands on Expertise - Asp.Net, C#, MVC, Entity Framework, Web API Beginner Level Epertise - .Net Core, Phone Gap, Cordova, Ionic 3

Scripting Language – Angular 2+, AngularJs, JavaScript, jQuery

Database - MSSQL

Web Development - HTML, HTML5, CSS

Version Control - TFS, GIT

Domain - Media, Inventory Management, Finance.

# **ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES**

My responsibilities include Requirement analysis, interacting with Customers for requirement clarification, providing the estimation and delivering the codes within the timeframe.

Developed complex modules based on business requirement using various Microsoft Technologies and did code reviews, code optimizations and gave demos to client

Worked as a Subject Matter Expert in the Project and have conducted KT's to the betterment of fellow colleagues.

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

## **Certified SCRUM MASTER**

05/2021

## **EDUCATION**

## **B.E in INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY**

University Of Mumbai (06/2014)

H.S.C

Maharashtra State Board (02/2009)

S.S.C.

Maharashtra State Board (03/2007)

I do hereby declare that the above information is true to the best of my knowledge.